{"componentChunkName":"component---src-pages-projects-js","path":"/Projects/","result":{"data":{"allProjectInfoCsv":{"edges":[{"node":{"title":"AI for Early Detection of Pancreatic Cancer","org":"Galen Health","members":"Logan Nye, Kushagra Agarwal","timeframe":"","problem":"Pancreatic cancer is one of the most deadly cancers that exist. Of the 500,000 people diagnosed each year, only ~10% will survive another 12 months.","solution":"It turns out that pancreatic cancer is treatable if we can catch it early, but we have never had an effective screening test to do so. We are building the first one: an AI system that screens patient health records for early warning signs of pancreatic cancer.","link":"www.galenhealth.org"}},{"node":{"title":"Anonym","org":"Individual Project","members":"Yara Samad","timeframe":"2021","problem":"Bias in the hiring process - hurts employers and employees.","solution":"A recruitment platform that reduces bias in the hiring process from application to interview to onboarding - ensuring equal opportunities for all and a more effective workplace.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Catalog Website: The Black Archive","org":"Tech4Society","members":"Cody Berger, Lucy Knox, Ivy Li, Cheyu Tu, Annie Zhang","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"Alma|Lewis, our community partner, has an archive collection of books, articles, and ephemera relating to Black art and history, called the Black Archive. They want an online catalog of their archive for scholars and researchers to browse.","solution":"We are developing a searchable online catalog website for the Black Archive, using open-source frameworks. The website will be easy to maintain and update.","link":"https://www.almalewis.org/the-black-archive/, https://cmutech4society.github.io/collectionbuilder-gh/"}},{"node":{"title":"CMU Global Business Brigades","org":"Individual Project","members":"Sebin Eichel Choi, Lindsay Lamberti, Shruti Srinivasan, Jack Herbert","timeframe":"Fall 2023","problem":"Lack of community banks results in little to no savings amongst community members, limited access to sufficient affordable credit, lack of financial literacy and leadership, and slow economic growth amongst communities.","solution":"Global Business Brigades’ solution ultimately creates financial opportunities in remote, rural, and under-resourced areas of Honduras, Panama, Ghana, and Nicaragua. Overall, we aim to promote micro-enterprise development through administrative and technical assistance. Specifically, in Panama, we aid in forming community banks and/or locals’ own credit and savings cooperatives, which addresses the financial needs of rural families who don’t have access to formal sources of loans or savings.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Embelli","org":"CMU","members":"Hirani Sattenapalli, Ella Lee, Ritu Pathak","timeframe":"Spring 2024","problem":"Street trash is a very pressing problem in many parts of the world, especially urban areas that have high populations. Although some governments have established cleaning programs that use human labor to beautify the streets, such programs are costly and require significant human labor and time.","solution":"The solution we present to this issue is a street trash cleaning robot that collects specific trash items and works on sidewalks/ large public spaces. The robot detects and collects specific trash items that we have defined while operating autonomously on the sidewalks.","link":"https://course.ece.cmu.edu/~ece500/projects/s24-teame4/"}},{"node":{"title":"Journal AI","org":"Individual Project","members":"Advaith Sridhar, Marlies Goes, Saumya Gandhi, Sharang Pai","timeframe":"Spring 2023","problem":"We wanted to solve a problem in the digital mental health space. Specifically, we wanted to improve the experience of journaling, which has been shown to have tremendous mental health benefits.","solution":"We developed Journal AI: an AI guided journaling app that helps users reflect deeper in their journaling process through personalized responses to their journal entries including positive affirmation and follow up questions.","link":"https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.journalai.mvp&hl=en_US"}},{"node":{"title":"Lean On Us, CMU!","org":"Lean On Me at CMU","members":"Justin Wangying Lam, Sydney Sun, Kaylee Hong, Isaac Li","timeframe":"Spring 2021 - Spring 2024","problem":"Many university students, including those at Carnegie Mellon University, experience social isolation and loneliness, which can adversely impact their physical and mental health. These feelings of loneliness may arise from increasing social and academic demands in a new, unfamiliar setting. The need for a robust social support system is crucial in helping students build up resilience and satisfaction of their overall well-being.","solution":"The goal of Lean On Me is to provide an easily accessible, confidential peer-to-peer support textline. Supporters on the line help students navigate emotional distress, relationship issues, and other non-crisis problems. Our organization is run by students, for students, and with students, as we move towards a more sustainable community that prioritizes student’s mental health needs.","link":"https://www.instagram.com/leanonme.cmu, https://leanonmechat.wixsite.com/carnegiemellon"}},{"node":{"title":"Metaverse Museum","org":"Individual Project","members":"Selena Meng, Yifan Wang, Eunice Yang, Nicole Huang","timeframe":"Fall 2022 - Spring 2023","problem":"While two-thirds of museums struggle to recover their attendance rates to the pre-pandemic level, over 2 million underprivileged students remain deprived of access to art education.","solution":"We aim to democratize access to art education by transforming museums into online VR exhibitions enriched by AI-driven features. This will provide an affordable, interactive, and customized learning experience for people regardless of background.","link":"http://metaverse-museum.art/, https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c476hFRjYHI, https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Cbyz2-bYncc2fUXw2Ac2usn6XSk1DRnN8iOiOU5ORIw/edit?usp=sharing"}},{"node":{"title":"Pro Bono Consulting: Carnegie Museum of Art","org":"Tepper Pro Bono Consulting Club","members":"Aakarsh Palnitkar, Diksha Dubey, Mrunank Bobde, Bhrigu Kapur, Usman Khan","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"The Carnegie Museum of Art is struggling to increase it's online ticket revenue limiting it's ability to expand its customer base.","solution":"Targeted marketing strategies for wide variety of users, aim to identify effective revenue streams through benchmarking, and analyze website usability","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Reading Ready Pittsburgh Mobile Library","org":"Freedom By Design","members":"Gabrielle Benson, Hannah Haytko-Desalvo, Nathan Cottrell, David Decker, Zoe Botta, Youstina Riad, Silvia Kim","timeframe":"Spring 2023","problem":"Reading Ready Pittsburgh is a local organization dedicated to giving kids and families the resources they need to prep them for reading at school, and as part of their series of events throughout the year, volunteers often set up booths at outdoor venues. Although the current setup works, volunteers at these events often need to carry heavy boxes long distances to set up and engagement from passersby could increase with a more interesting and inviting display of the books.","solution":"Freedom by Design has worked with Reading Ready Pittsburgh to design and construct a small mobile library that both allows for easy setup at outdoor community events as well as be inviting for children to come and pick up a book. Additionally, the mobile library is designed to be portable and light enough for a singular person the set up and operate.","link":"https://www.cmuaias.org/fbd, https://www.readingreadypittsburgh.org/"}},{"node":{"title":"Robots Beyond Assistance","org":"CMU + Multiple Care Homes","members":"Hugo Simao, Neeta Khanuja, Catarina Gamboa","timeframe":"This project is related to 2 PhD projects that started in 2021and will be going on until 2025/6.","problem":"Special Olympics Pennsylvania Three Rivers Region has been trying to expand their operations for their events in the last year as they recognize that they have had trouble getting younger athletes involved in their Unified Champion schools programs (average age of a Special Olympics Athlete is 34 years old), increasing local engagement and donations for their Annual Polar Plunge Fundraiser which has takes place at the Acrisure Stadium, and lastly, increasing engagement for the Western Spring Sectional: a regional competition that has been hosted on CMU campus since 2016 which does not garner heavy CMU student and faculty involvement.","solution":"CMU Special Olympics has been working with the Special Olympics Three Rivers Region to target these operations, and collaborated with Cornell University’s students to identify marketing strategies for their Unified Champion Schools and targeting local family oriented centers for the Polar Plunge, which helped surpass this year’s fundraising goal over $1 million for the first time! CMU Special Olympics was also invited to visit Special Olympics’ Fall Fest at Villanova University last semester, from which we were inspired to create our own official student-run effort to bolster CMU volunteering and engagement for the Western Spring Sectional competition taking place on April 20th, 2024.","link":"https://www.instagram.com/cmu.specialolympics?igsh=MTZiYzRoaW0wODRtdQ=="}},{"node":{"title":"Sew Sustainable","org":"Individual Project","members":"Katrina Darms","timeframe":"Fall 2022 - Spring 2025","problem":"The fashion industry is incredibly polluting, and fast fashion clothes are lower quality than ever. Clothing gets worn out and then must either be repaired or replaced.","solution":"Teaching campus community how to mend/alter/fix their clothing and accessories, to reduce waste, save money, and improve the fit/style of wardrobe. Leading a StuCo and ~bimonthly workshops","link":"https://www.instagram.com/mendwithkat?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&igsh=ZDNlZDc0MzIxNw=="}},{"node":{"title":"Special Olympics at CMU","org":"Special Olympics at CMU","members":"Aditi Shimpi, Dillon Guludec, Emilie He, Saraj Dillon, Kai Yamamoto, Chengtao Zheng, Nanaki Singh, Avishi Sahoo, Ruhani Patel","timeframe":"Fall 2022 - Spring 2023","problem":"Special Olympics Pennsylvania Three Rivers Region has been trying to expand their operations for their events in the last year as they recognize that they have had trouble getting younger athletes involved in their Unified Champion schools programs (average age of a Special Olympics Athlete is 34 years old), increasing local engagement and donations for their Annual Polar Plunge Fundraiser which has takes place at the Acrisure Stadium, and lastly, increasing engagement for the Western Spring Sectional: a regional competition that has been hosted on CMU campus since 2016 which does not garner heavy CMU student and faculty involvement.","solution":"CMU Special Olympics has been working with the Special Olympics Three Rivers Region to target these operations, and collaborated with Cornell University’s students to identify marketing strategies for their Unified Champion Schools and targeting local family oriented centers for the Polar Plunge, which helped surpass this year’s fundraising goal over $1 million for the first time! CMU Special Olympics was also invited to visit Special Olympics’ Fall Fest at Villanova University last semester, from which we were inspired to create our own official student-run effort to bolster CMU volunteering and engagement for the Western Spring Sectional competition taking place on April 20th, 2024.","link":"https://www.instagram.com/cmu.specialolympics?igsh=MTZiYzRoaW0wODRtdQ=="}},{"node":{"title":"Sustainable Earth","org":"Sustainable Earth","members":"Nathan Cottrell, Jose Echeverria, Jessica Wu","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"Sustainability is an intimidating word, one that we seem to see most commonly on company websites, or carried out by large-scale organizations. Rarely do students seem to think about sustainability on a personal level, much less how it affects their local community.","solution":"Our hydroponics doghouse is a proof-of-concept showing how sustainable gardening can be achieved on a local scale, both individually and in the Pittsburgh region. Our goal is to get CMU students to think about the role the environment plays in their daily lives and how they can carry out sustainable practices.","link":""}},{"node":{"title":"DFA x YMCA Project","org":"Design for America","members":"Ish Acharya, Jodie Yang, Wendy Yu","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"We wanted to help the YMCA connect youth with similar social justice-related interests and projects so that they were more motivated to get involved in their communities.","solution":"We created the UI for a social media app that would allow youth to post their projects, connect with other youths with similar passions and experience, and find mentors and resources from experienced community members.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Moneythink CMU","org":"Design for America","members":"Samantha Joseph, Michael Maxwell","timeframe":"Fall 2022 - Spring 2023","problem":"Our client, Moneythink, realized that they had no central place to direct their marketing and accumulate all their resources (notes, lectures, contact information, etc.)","solution":"We developed a website that will contain all of Moneythink's resources to increase accessibility and allow more users to learn and connect with this organization.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"LDA of PA 1-1 Tutoring Scheduling","org":"Design for America","members":"Prina Doshi, Jasmine Dong, Emma Tong, Alanna Cao, Tracy Yang, Naza Monjur","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"LDA of PA is an organization that promotes knowledge and awareness about learning and attention disabilities in the Pennsylvania region, through a variety of programs and services including 1-1 tutoring and group tutoring opportunities. Currently, the organization utilizes manual methods to schedule and track tutoring sessions, leading to inefficiencies in scheduling and difficulty supporting the size of the program.","solution":"To more easily schedule tutoring sessions, we have researched and recommended a schedule and appointment management software that will allow LDA of PA to automate reminders, easily find tutors' and students' schedules, and track student progress.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"SEEDS","org":"Design for America","members":"Michael Li, Christina Moon, Elly Young","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"SEEDS is a non-profit sustainability organization with a mission of promoting energy efficiency, renewable energy, and sustainable lifestyles in their community, and by talking with their executive director the past semester we derived our design goal of reimagining a solution to improve community engagement and increase community awareness about energy efficiency practices for using digital tools.","solution":"Our solution is using SEEDS' current resource about energy saving tips and tricks, we translated it into an interactive calculator which is also printable so it is accessible on different mediums. This will be engaging for user learn about practices they are able to implement right away in their homes.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Multiplying Good Pittsburgh","org":"Design for America","members":"Anna Mathews, Autumn Qiu, Emily Jiang, Evelynn Chen, Kajal Mehta, Karen Gonzalez-Cifuentes, Ramitha Mallavarapu, Vicky Chen","timeframe":"Fall 2022 - Spring 2023","problem":"Our problem space is centered around how we can empower Multiplying Good Pittsburgh Students in Action (SIA) Teams to reach out for needed resources and enable local professionals (Changemakers) to provide support and guidance.","solution":"Our solution is an Airtable database, featuring bios of local professionals (Changemakers), facilitating connections between Students in Action (SIA) teams and Changemakers capable of offering support for their community projects.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Engaging with the Nexus of Civic Engagement","org":"Design for America","members":"Amanda Witt, Kailey Hu, Serena Cai, Ainika Hou, Erika Egliskis","timeframe":"Spring 2023","problem":"The Nexus is a new addition to UC specific to connecting students who are interested in civic engagement to resources such as a collaborative space as well as service opportunities. Since the Nexus is new, many students are unaware of its uses or even its existence.","solution":"WIP but leaning towards flyers designed to target students, social media/newletters to circulate these materials.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Empowering Artists with GPAC","org":"Design for America","members":"Avani Guduri, Alisa Lo, Allison Zhang, Chloe He, Eunice Lee, Sophie Hao, Sulli Yatabe","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"The Greater Pittsburgh Arts Council is looking to empower Pittsburgh artists to be self-advocates in their communities. While artists value advocacy, they don't have the time nor knowledge for it, nor do they trust the impact they can have through it.","solution":"Our solution introduces advocacy to events that artists currently spend time on and value: networking events—after all, advocacy is stronger together. We deliver information to help artists advocate through bite-sized infographic cards, facilitate conversation to spark action through networking bingo and interactive collage boards, and show artists the real impact the stories they've wrote on postcards can have on legislation.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"Mental Health Matters","org":"Wellness Initiatives, Here For You, Lean On Me at CMU, Mindfulness Room","members":"Aiwen Chen, Justin Wangying Lam, Gabriel Mendez-Sanders, Vivian Lin, Ash Gelber, Kel-Li Chen, Harsh Agarwal","timeframe":"Spring 2024 - Current","problem":"Adolescent mental health continues to worsen, following the social and economic difficulties caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. College life is full of uncertainties – fear of job opportunities, academic and peer pressure, and lack of social connections formed by students. The mental health problems that young adults face are numerous, especially at CMU.","solution":"The Mental Health Cohort is a coalition of on-campus mental health organizations, where we share knowledge about existing wellness initiatives, brainstorm ideas, and tackle the biggest mental health concerns facing campus communities. It also provides a space where members can be vulnerable and share their challenges in mental health advocacy. Our large, on-campus events, such as the Stress Less Fest, are also collectively designed to promote the narrative of self-care bettering the lives of CMU students.","link":"N/A"}},{"node":{"title":"SUDS & BikePGH: How socioeconomic factors affect biking patterns in Pittsburgh","org":"BikePGH","members":"Ayushman Srivastava, Elijah Forcucci, Smrithi Krishnaswamy, Chirapon Taepaisitphongse, Wesley Kane, Andy Lee, Joyce Lam, Best Pantusen","timeframe":"Fall 2023 - Spring 2024","problem":"This project is a bid to enhance Pittsburgh's biking infrastructure by studying the patterns of bike commuters across multiple lenses such as socia-ecomomic status, household size, age, occupation, gender etc.","solution":"We are working with BikePGH and the office of the Mayor of Pittsburgh to a) increase awareness about the existing gaps in the biking infrastructure and b) suggest feasibale improvements to this infrastructure by plotting a multiple layers of data on ArcGIS and leveraging that to drive meaningful conversations that ultimately result in data-driven decisions around making Pittsburgh more bike-friendly and bike-accessible","link":"https://bikepgh.org/resources/maps-guides-more/map-routes/"}}]}},"pageContext":{}},"staticQueryHashes":[]}